Rong Zheng

(+1) 954-600-0861 | rzheng@fau.edu | U.S Citizen | https://zhengronggift.github.io

CAREER PROFILE

Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience in Embedded System Development. Experienced in both manual and automated software testing methodologies. Core competencies include Software Development, Software Hardware Architectures, User Interface Design, CI/CD, Integration Test, and Unit Test.

EXPERIENCE

Lockheed Martin Orlando, FL

Software Engineer Associate (Missile and Fire Control)

June 2020 — Present

- Working in embedded C++ programming environment to aid in telemetry collection, message handling, and data processing for Joint-Air-To-Ground Missile (JAGM) program.
- Architect, design, and develop new software features and hardware devices into internal tool frameworks to
 enhance product capabilities. Reduced latency of data processing by 50%, resolved runtime errors, and
 improved memory utilization on the tools by performing root cause analysis and test driven development
 methodology.
- Setup and enhance gitlab CI/CD pipeline using yml script to automate build and deployment process for different environments.
- <u>Tools:</u> C++, C, Python, QT Creator, GIT, CMake, Docker, Device Drivers, TCP/Multicast UDP, Shell Script, Automation Script, Agile, JIRA, Confluence, Linux, Windows

Ford Motor Company

Sunrise, FL

<u>Manufacturing Software Developer Co-op</u> (SYNC Infotainment System)

Jan 2020 — May 2020

- Technical debug, troubleshoot, and log analysis to determine causes for software failures during manufacturing runs using C++ on Linux, batch script on Windows, and bash shell script on device builds.
- Provided general status and information about software sanity test results to the Software Development Manager and Product Development Team.
- Tools: C++, GIT, Agile, SonarQube, I2C, UART, SPI, QNX, JIRA, Jenkins, RTOS, Shell Script

Randstad Technologies US

Fort Lauderdale, FL

Embedded Software Engineer Intern (Caterpillar Inc.)

May 2019 — Jan 2020

- Provided unit tests for AIS (Autonomous Infrastructure Software) and CPM (Caterpillar Production Measurement). Debugged the application software using Object Oriented programming in C++.
- Developed new features based on user stories and loaded onto an ECM (Engine Control Module) for integration testing by using SSH.
- Tool: C++, GIT, Agile, SSH, Unix/Linux, Eclipse, Engine Control Module (ECM/ECU), CAN Bus

Hispanic Serving Institute

Davie, FL

Student Mentor

Jan 2019 — May 2020

- Conducted one-on-one tutoring sessions for college students in Algebra, Pre-Calculus, Calculus I, Calculus II, Java, C++, and Intro to C.
- Tools: C++, C, Java, Python, JavaScript, Code Debugging

EDUCATION

Florida Atlantic University

Bachelors in Computer Engineering, Bachelors in Computer Science

Graduated May 2020

GPA: 3.77 / 4.00, Magna Cum Laude

PROJECTS

Automated Rescue Transportation Unit

Jan 2019 — Dec 2019

- Designed a dual control system for an on the water rescue unit by using Radio Control and WIFI network communication with Arduino Nano and Raspberry Pi.
- Implemented a user interface by using Node.JS for serial port communication for motor control.
- Tools: C, Node.JS, Python, Multimeter, Nginx, GIT, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap